Kevin Murphy Front-End Developer

Profile

Kevin has over 9 years experience building web application UI and strong skills in React. Additionally, he has been involved in many practical MERN projects, which is a great bonus to his skills. He is a quick learner, able to pick up new skills and take on a variety of projects and roles with relative ease. He excels at collaborating with his teammates.

Skills

```
TypeScript | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | React | React Hooks | Redux | Context API
React Query | Axios | React Hook Form | Formik | Joi | i18n | Lodash | Web3.js
Ethers.js | React Bootstrap | MUI Core | Styled Component | TailwindCSS | SCSS
Jest | Mocha | Node.js | Express.js | MongoDB | C/C++
Data Structure & Algorithm | AWS | Git | GitHub | Team Player | Peer Support
Stress Management | Time Management | Quality-driven | Communication
```

Experience

Front-End Developer, *Scopic Software*

Oct 2022 – present | Remote

- Created a mobile responsive user experience with CSS flex box that allowed cross-platform accessibility to the website on any device, with primary use on mobile.
- Built API following RESTful standards to allow users to submit information by storing data in MongoDB.
- Partnered with data science to develop the front end for a product recommendation that increased user time on page by 3 minutes.
- Curated over 50 website changes to increase the user flow and understanding of all platform capabilities and features.

Application Developer, Owny

Apr 2020 – Oct 2022 | Remote

- Quickly got up to speed 120% with existing web applications spanning using Node.js.
- Collaborated with the rest of the team to quickly iterate on product ideas and add 4 new features.
- Delivered reliable, well-structured code that can easily be understood by other team members.
- Created new application prototypes from scratch and well as maintained reliable production system.

Senior Web Developer, Softrick Solutions

Apr 2019 – Apr 2020 Corpus Christi, TX

- Worked with product owners to understand desired application capabilities and testing scenarios.
- Participated in internal and external technology communities, and mentored 2 members of the engineering community.
- Led the craftsmanship, availability, resilience, and scalability of solutions.
- Encouraged innovation, implementation of cutting-edge technologies, inclusion, outsideof-the-box thinking, teamwork, and diversity.

Junior Web Developer, Softrick Solutions

Mar 2017 - Apr 2019

Corpus Christi, TX

- Performed a variety of technical administration, development, and support functions for Information Services.
- Worked with customers, vendors, consultants, and other Information Services staff in performing their duties.
- Built logical and efficient solutions and fixed 4 issues in user input forms.
- Developed tutorials to teach new interns the best practices in MERN stack.

Web Developer Intern, Softrick Solutions

Sep 2016 - Mar 2017

Corpus Christi, TX

- Integrated third-party API to the existing website.
- Helped plan, design, and build new user interfaces with React.
- Built interactive and responsive user interfaces that facilitate end users' interaction.
- Participated in the conceptualization and wireframing of new interfaces.

Education

B.S. Computer Science,

2016 | Corpus Christi, TX

UMN College of Science and Engineering

Certificates

TripleByte Engineering Certificate *⊘*

JavaScript, React, Data Structure & Algorithm

Interests

Soccer | Medium Blog | Guitar